Shengkun (Bryson) Tang

Email: shengkuntangwork@gmail.com GitHub: https://github.com/Tangshengku

Website: https://tangshengku.github.io/ Last Update: 06.14 2023

Research Interests

My research interests lie on **Landable Generative Artificial Intelligence**, focusing on the **Resource Efficiency** and **Decision Reliability** of AI System. My research covers the whole pipeline of Generative AI system, providing full-stack solutions from theoretical optimization methods and data-centric strategies to the development of efficient deep learning techniques and the codesign of algorithms and hardware.

- 1) Resource-Efficient Training & Inference Algorithms
- 2) Data Optimization to Improve Data Quality & Efficiency
- 3) Reliable & Scalable Methods for AI Systems
- 4) Algorithm-Hardware Co-design for Acceleration
- 5) Application: Multi-Modal (Vision-Language), Uni-Modal (NLP, CV)

Education

North Carolina State University

Raleigh, USA

Ph.D. in Computer Science

08. 2023 -

Mentor: Dongkuan Xu

Wuhan University

Wuhan, China

B.E. in Remote Sensing and Information Engineering (Top1 in Asia)

Bachelor 9. 2018 – 6. 2022

Mentor: Jian Yao

Publications

You Need Multiple Exiting: Dynamic Early Exiting for Accelerating Unified Vision Language Model

Shengkun Tang, Yaqing Wang, Zhenglun Kong, Tianchi Zhang, Yao Li, Caiwen Ding, Yanzhi Wang, Ethan Liang, Dongkuan Xu.

(CVPR 2023) The IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition

DDR-Net: Learning Multi-Stage Multi-View Stereo With Dynamic Depth Range

Puyuan Yi*, **Shengkun Tang***, Jian Yao.

Preprint

(* equal contribution)

Scale-Robust Deep-Supervision Network for Mapping Building Footprints from High-Resolution Remote Sensing Images

Haonan Guo, Xin Su, Shengkun Tang, Bo Du, Liangpei Zhang

IEEE Journal of Selected Topics in Applied Earth Observations and Remote Sensing

Research Experience

Efficient Vision Language Model via Early Exiting

Mentor: Dongkuan Xu (North Caroline State University) Yaqing Wang (Google Research)

Remote, 5. 2022 - Now

- 1) Apply early exiting strategy into vision language models to increase the inference speed.
- 2) Propose modality decomposition to split vision and language information and early exiting in different modalities for different vision language tasks.
- 3) Utilize Cosine Similarity as metric to decide exiting layers in order to early exit in both encoder and decoder of Seq2Seq model.
- 4) Our model can reduce 50% computation while 99% performance is preserved and achieves the best trade-off comparing with other methods.

Efficient Multimodal Learning Software and Hardware Co-design

Collaborator: Tianchi Zhang (Master in University of Michigan)

Mentor: Dongkuan Xu (North Caroline State University)

Remote, 6. 2022 - Now

- 1) Aim to optimize software and hardware simultaneously to improve the efficiency of multi-modal model.
- 2) Utilize input token pruning to shrink input token into static size which is hardware-friendly. The hardware is able to allocate resources in advance and increase the inference speed.

Research on Multi-View Stereo in Computer Vision and Remote Sensing Laboratory (CVRS Lab)

Mentor: Professor Jian Yao (Wuhan University)

Wuhan, 6. 2020 - 6. 2022

- 1) In CVRS Lab, I mainly worked on 3D reconstruction, specifically, multi-view stereo (MVS).
- 2) Dynamic Depth Range Network (DDR-Net) was proposed in order to solve the issues related to strong-light and textureless scenes and achieved SoTA performance on standard open-source dataset.
- 3) In this work, I wrote code and did most of the experiments. I still wrote the paper and modified it for several times.

Synthetic Aperture Radar (SAR) Object Detection and Standard Dataset Construction

Mentor: Professor Xin Su (Wuhan University)

Wuhan, 9. 2019 - 9.2021

- 1) Leader of this project.
- 2) The major task was dataset construction and proposing new model for SAR images which are completely different from optical images.

3) labeled most of the high-resolution SAR images which are hard to image interpretation by eyes. New model targeted on tiny object detection in SAR images.

Work Experience

System Developer in Intelligent Automotive Group (IAG), SenseTime

Shenzhen, 9. 2021 - Now

- 1) Intelligent Automotive Group builds a large system for self-driving including localization, reconstruction, perception and so on.
- 2) My work is located at combining all algorithm modules and apply these functions during real scenario. Also, I am required to transfer our system into different platforms such as NVIDIA ORIN and Huawei MDC.

System Developer in Smart City Group (SCG), SenseTime

Shenzhen, 5. 2022 – 9. 2022

- 1) My project in Smart City Group is 3D reconstruction.
- 2) Build cluster resource manager engine to manage the resource of cluster.
- 3) Deploy the 3D reconstruction algorithms into clusters and schedule the resources allocated for a specific algorithm.
- 4) Present a 3D reconstruction algorithm system with high parallelism.

Internship

Vision Algorithm Developer Internship in SenseTime

Shenzhen, 6. 2021 – 10. 2021

- 1) Two major projects: Chess Robot and Baby Monitor.
- 2) Deployment of deep learning algorithm. We need to utilize Python to train and evaluate our model for resource-limited devices.
- 3) Implemented the whole projects in C++ and deploy the algorithm to the specific platform like RockChips.

Projects

Automotive Driving System Platform Construction

Shenzhen, 9.2022 - Now

- 1) Self-driving is a complicate system which contains localization, prediction, pilot modules and so on. A unified platform is needed to control every module on the real road.
- 2) The direction of our project is to design a control system that is able to be deployed on real cars. Right now the car deployed our system can self drive without the interaction with humans in highways.

3D Space Modeling and Rendering

Shenzhen, 5.2022 – 9.2022

- 1) This is an official project we worked for China Southern Power Grid company.
- 2) The task is reconstructing the 3D indoor scenes such as engine room, working areas.

3) The mission of our team is to optimize the reconstruction algorithm in cluster environment. By planning the Dag map, we maximine the degree of parallelism.

Health Monitor Device: Baby Monitor

Shenzhen, 6.2021 - 10.2021

- 1) This project targets on designing a health product to monitor baby status with pure vision images.
- 2) Propose a novel algorithm to detect breath rate and heart rate with thermal images (close source because of product competition).
- 3) My work is to deploy all algorithms into edge devices.

Chinese Chess Robot: SenseRobot

Shenzhen, 6.2021 - 10.2021

- 1) The first project during my internship in SenseTime.
- 2) The goal is to build a human-interactive robot that is able to play Chinese chess with users.
- 3) Despite pure game algorithm, our robot can also move the chess in the chess-board on own. The robot is selling hot in Jingdong Mall.

Contests

Baidu Astar Developer Competition

2020

Ranking: 7/2305(teams)

- 1) The task of Baidu Astar 2020 is traffic signs and surveillance cameras detection and matching.
- 2) I was in charge of detection task. I solved the problems of long-tail data imbalance by using my own data argumentation strategy and detect surveillance cameras more accurately.
- 3) We got into the final session and ranked 7 out of 2305teams.

Mathematical Contest in Modeling

2020

Prize: S level

- 1) As team leader, I dispatch the task to my teammates and collaborate with my classmates remotely to finish the modeling task.
- 2) Analyze the structure of the task and simplify the modeling. The main experiments are conducted based on Matlab.

Professional Services

Conference Reviewer

KDD 2023 AAAI 2023

Awards

National Endeavor Fellowship Outstanding student scholarship Wuhan, 2019

Wuhan, 2019

Skills **Programming**

Python, C/C++, PyTorch, Matlab.

OS: Linux, Mac, Windows.

Language

Chinese (Mother tongue), English (Working language)

References

Jian Yao, Ph.D.

Professor

School of Remote Sensing and Information Engineering

Wuhan University

Email: jian.yao@whu.edu.cn

Homepage: https://www.scholat.com/jianyao.en

Relationship: Research Advisor during Undergraduate in Wuhan University

Xin Su, Ph.D.

Assistant Professor

School of Remote Sensing and Information Engineering

Wuhan University

Email: xinsu.rs@whu.edu.cn

Homepage: http://jszy.whu.edu.cn/xinsurs/zhCN/index.htm

Relationship: Research Advisor during Undergraduate in Wuhan University,

Head Teacher

Yaqing Wang, Ph.D.

Researcher

Google Research

Email: yaqingwang@google.com

Homepage: https://yaqingwang.github.io/

Relationship: Mentor in Project: Efficient Vision Language Model via Early

Exiting